Guide to the Joseph Bruchac Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- November 1996 Acquisition, 1959-1998; 78.25 linear feet (83 boxes)
  - Subject Files
    - Recently Completed Projects to 1996
      - National Forest Service: Conservation Lifesongs, 1992 (Box 60)
      - Native American Folklore Project, 1990 (Box 60)
      - Nature Company: Singing of Earth, 1992-1993 (Box 60)
      - Navajo Community College Press, 1984 (Box 60)
      - Nebraska University, Press of, 1994 (Box 60)
      - The New England Press, 1991 (Box 61)
      - New Hampshire Historical Society, 1995 (Box 61)
      - New Hampshire Humanities, 1994 (Box 61)
      - The New Press, 1995 (Box 61)
      - New York State Museum: publications, 1988 (Box 61)
      - Northeast Indian Quarterly, 1991 (Box 61)
      - Northland Publishing, 1990-1996 (Box 61)
      - Oklahoma University Press, 1994-1995 (Box 61)
      - Oklahoma (Kenny Book), 1994 (Box 61)
      - Orion Books, 1987-1994; 2 (Box 61)
      - Oryx Press: Native American Folk Stories, 1992-1995; 2 (Box 61)
      - Prentice Hall, 1995 (Box 61)
      - The Plains Indians (proof), 1994 (Box 61)
      - Parabola, 1991-1996; 3 (Box 61)
      - Pen Multicultural Committee, 1992 (Box 61)
      - Prentice Hall, 1992-1995 (Box 61)
      - Raintree Press, 1989 (Box 61)
      - Joshua Morris Publishing (Reader's Digest), 1992-1993 (Box 61)
      - Re-educating our Imagination: Men and Feminism, 1991 (Box 61)
      - Rethinking Schools, 1994 (Box 61)
      - Sail, 1990-1992; 2 (Box 62)
      - Scholastic, 1992-1993 (Box 62)
      - Scott Foresman, 1991-1992 (Box 62)
      - Search for Equality, 1996 (Box 62)
      - Small Press, undated (Box 62)
      - Smithsonian Magazine, 1994 (Box 62)
      - Smithsonian Institution Press, 1992 (Box 62)
      - Smithsonian Runner, 1992 (Box 62)
      - Soaring with Ravens, 1994 (Box 62)
      - SOS (recipe poem anthology), 1995 (Box 62)
      - St. Martin's Press, 1994-1995 (Box 62)
      - Studies in American Indian Literature, 1989-1990 (Box 62)
      - Story Tree, 1992-1996 (Box 62)
      - Symphony Space, 1992 (Box 62)
      - Storm Belt, undated (Box 62)
      - Christine Shrader, 1991-1994 (Box 62)
      - Survival This Way: reviews, 1988-1989 (Box 62)
      - Sundance Institute, 1995-1996; 2 (Box 62)
      - Syracuse University Press, 1993-1995 (Box 62)
      - Tale Trader, 1996 (Box 62)
      - Tamaqua Native Writing Issue, 1990-1991 (Box 62)
      - Time Life Books, undated (Box 62)
      - Union Institute, undated (Box 62)
      - Vermont History, 1994-1995 (Box 62)
      - Viking Children's Books, 1995 (Box 62)
      - Visible Ink Press, 1995 (Box 62)
      - Wings of Peace, On the, 1992-1993 (Box 62)
      - Wisconsin Academy Review, 1992 (Box 62)
      - Wordcraft Circle, 1996 (Box 62)
      - Writers, Inc., 1993-1994 (Box 63)
      - Yellow Moon Press, 1989-1992 (Box 63)
      - Youtheatre Montreal, 1991-1992 (Box 63)
      - Yosemite calendar, 1992-1994; 3 (Box 63)
    - Native American Storytelling
      - Abenaki articles, etc., 1992 (Box 63)
      - Abenaki clippings, 1988-1991 (Box 63)
      - Abenaki/European: similarities and differences, undated (Box 63)
      - Arctic to Amazonia Alliance, 1991 (Box 63)
      - Abenaki Culture Exchange Project, 1992 (Box 63)
      - Abenaki stories, undated (Box 63)
      - Abenaki walk, 1991-1992 (Box 63)
      - Akwesasne Freedom School, 1993 (Box 63)
      - Akwesasne: Aboriginal Science and Math Pilot Project, 1992 (Box 63)
      - American Indian Archaeological Institute, undated (Box 63)
      - American Indian Dictionary essays, 1988-1989 (Box 63)
      - Annharte Marie Baker, 1991 (Box 63)
      - Fred Bigjim, 1993 (Box 63)
      - Big Mountain, 1981-1989; 2 (Box 63)
      - The People Speak, 1984 (Box 63)
      - Peter Blue Cloud, undated (Box 63)
      - Songs, BMI agreement, 1971 (Box 63)
      - Bowman genealogy, undated (Box 63)
      - Celestial Bear, 1993 (Box 63)
      - Eileen Charbonneau, 1993 (Box 63)
      - The Circle of Stories: Workshop, 1993 (Box 63)
      - Charley Colcord, 1987-1991; 4 (Box 64)
      - Council for American Indian Interpretation, undated (Box 64)
      - Council Press, 1996 (Box 64)
      - Jesse Cornplanter, manuscript, 1992 (Box 64)
      - D'Arcy McNickle Center, 1990-1991 (Box 64)
      - Djerassi Foundation, 1992 (Box 64)
      - Essays, 1995 (Box 64)
      - Essays by various writers on Native American literature, 1982 (Box 64)
      - Finch, Kate study plan, 1991 (Box 64)
      - Forbes, Jack, 1994 (Box 64)
      - Futures for Children, 1993 (Box 64)
      - American Indian Games, undated (Box 64)
      - Ganondagan, undated (Box 64)
      - Geneology guide, undated (Box 64)
      - Gish, Robert, 1992 (Box 64)
      - Haskell Junior College, undated (Box 64)
      - Hathaway, Baxter, 1983 (Box 64)
      - Heidelbaugh, Tom, 1994 (Box 64)
      - Henry, Gordon, 1992-1993 (Box 64)
      - Henson, Lance, 1993 (Box 64)
      - H.O.N.O.R., 1993-1994 (Box 64)
      - Hurd, Roy, undated (Box 64)
      - The Iroquois, 1988-1991 (Box 64)
      - Jacob, Murv, undated (Box 64)
      - Indian joke book, undated (Box 64)
      - Kahionhes, 1977-1995; 2 (Box 64)
      - Keewaydinoquay, 1987 (Box 65)
      - Larry Littlebird: Coyote Gathers his People, 1991 (Box 65)
      - Atian Lolo / Stephen Laurent, 1988-1989 (Box 65)
      - Liars Club, undated (Box 65)
      - Medium Rare, 1991 (Box 65)
      - Marshall, Joseph, 1995 (Box 65)
      - Medium Rare (Native American Journalists), undated (Box 65)
      - Monroem, Mark. An Indian in White America, 1994 (Box 65)
      - Monture, Joel, 1993 (Box 65)
      - Native American bibliography: middle and elementary schools, 1993 (Box 65)
      - Native American poetry bibliography, undated (Box 65)
      - Native American community of the capital district, 1991-1992 (Box 65)
      - Native American Film Festival: In the Spirit of Turtle Island, 1995 (Box 65)
      - Native American languages, 1994 (Box 65)
      - Native American literature, 1987 (Box 65)
      - Native American public broadcasting, 1991 (Box 65)
      - Native American screenwriters. Rudy Martin, 1993 (Box 65)
      - Native American storytellers, 1992-1993; 3 (Box 65)
      - Native Playwrights Newsletter, 1995 (Box 65)
      - Native Presses, 1990; 2 (Box 65)
      - Native Seeds, 1991-1993 (Box 65)
      - New England Indians, undated (Box 65)
      - New England Intertribal Village, undated (Box 65)
      - Niese, Henry (Eagle Voice Center), undated (Box 65)
      - Northland, 1993 (Box 65)
      - Odanak, 1989-1991; 2 (Box 65)
      - Odzihozo, undated (Box 65)
      - Okai, Atukwei, 1977-1979 (Box 65)
      - Juliene Osborne-McKnight, 1993-1994; 2 (Box 65)
      - Penn, Bill, 1992 (Box 66)
      - Perry, Robert, 1993 (Box 66)
      - Petitions: Native American information, 1991 (Box 66)
      - Purdy, John, 1996 (Box 66)
      - Reburial Journey, 1994-1995 (Box 66)
      - Ross, Allen. We Are All Related, 1988 (Box 66)
      - Saratoga Ghost Stories, 1991 (Box 66)
      - Saratoga Indian Stories, 1987-1988 (Box 66)
      - Schul, Bill. Life Song, 1994 (Box 66)
      - Serpent Mound, 1993 (Box 66)
      - Slavery (Indian), undated (Box 66)
      - Virginia Driving Hawk Sneve, 1994 (Box 66)
      - Sohappy, David, 1987 (Box 66)
      - Songs: transcriptions of Native American songs, 1988 (Box 66)
      - Stories from the Native Soil, 1987 (Box 66)
      - Storytellers, undated (Box 66)
      - Storytelling Workshops, 1984-1987; 3 (Box 66)
      - Sundance plays, 1995 (Box 66)
      - Means screenplay, 1995 (Box 66)
      - Montanex screenplay, 1995 (Box 66)
      - Lake Swamp: Tree of Place, 1995 (Box 66)
      - Iron Thunderhorse/Thunderbird Analysis, 1988 (Box 66)
      - Algonquin tale telling, 1995 (Box 66)
      - The Talking Stick, 1991 (Box 67)
      - The Tall Mountain Circle, 1994 (Box 67)
      - Trask, Haunani-Kay, 1993 (Box 67)
      - Turtle People, 1998 (Box 67)
      - Ward, Vaughn, 1992 (Box 67)
      - Welburn, Ron, 1991 (Box 67)
      - C. Schultz White & Benton White, 1995 (Box 67)
      - White Buffalo, 1986 (Box 67)
      - Wabenaki Heritage Outreach, 1992 (Box 67)
    - Other Subject Files
      - Essays, Yaddo, personal photos, undated (Box 67)
      - Eagle Computers, 1983 (Box 67)
      - American Book Award (Before Columbus 1984) (Box 67)
      - American Nature Writing Newsletter, 1994 (Box 67)
      - Adirondack Life, 1973-1983 (Box 67)
      - African Literature Association, 1980 (Box 67)
      - Alternative Materials for Libraries, 1987 (Box 67)
      - American Indian periodicals, 1982 (Box 67)
      - Ariadne's Thread: reading mailing list, 1982 (Box 67)
      - Artists with class, 1987 (Box 67)
      - Books, undated (Box 67)
      - Native American magazines and presses, 1981 (Box 67)
      - Essays on Native American literature, 1978 (Box 67)
      - Native American writing: bibliography, 1983 (Box 67)
      - Pirated Indian anthology, 1983 (Box 67)
      - Bear Tribe, 1982 (Box 67)
      - Calendars, 1983 (Box 67)
      - Canadian periodical publishers, 1983 (Box 67)
      - Essays, 1988 (Box 67)
      - Guggenheim, application for, 1983-1987 (Box 67)
      - Halley's comet, 1985-1986 (Box 68)
      - Hogan, Mike, 1979 (Box 68)
      - Intermedia profile, undated (Box 68)
      - Little magazines: information, undated (Box 68)
      - Maine Indians, undated; 4 (Box 68)
      - MLA, 1983-1984 (Box 68)
      - Multiple submissions, undated (Box 68)
      - Native Voices, 1981 (Box 68)
      - Ohio Arts Council, 1984 (Box 68)
      - Roth Publishing, undated (Box 68)
      - Self-publishing, 1990 (Box 68)
      - Small press, 1986 (Box 68)
      - Storytelling essays, undated (Box 68)
      - Vermont NEA, 1986 (Box 68)
      - Balliston High, 1986; 3 (Box 68)
      - Wrestling, 1988 (Box 68)
      - Writers' Colonies, 1984 (Box 68)
      - Woodcut, undated (Box 68)
      - Yaddo, 1985-1987; 2 (Box 68)
      - Profits and Prophets: Bard College, 1981 (Box 68)
  - Other Papers
    - Organizations, grant committees, and fellowships, 1982-1987; 29 (Box 69)
    - Organizations, grant committees, and fellowships, 1982-1985; 22 (Box 70)
    - Teaching materials, 1977-1985; 20 (Box 71)
    - Teaching materials, 1979-1984; 4 (Box 72)
    - Performances, readings, and workshops, 1979-1982; 25 (Box 72)
    - Performances, readings, and workshops, 1977-1986; 24 (Box 73)
    - Performances, readings, and workshops, 1982-1986; 23 (Box 74)
    - Performances, readings, and workshops, 1988-1989; 23 (Box 75)
    - Performances, readings, and workshops, 1989-1992; 23 (Box 76)
    - Performances, readings, and workshops, 1991; 24 (Box 77)
    - Performances, readings, and workshops, 1990-1993; 24 (Box 78)
    - Performances, readings and workshops, 1993-1995; 17 (Box 79)
    - Performances, readings and workshops, 1994-1995; 21 (Box 80)
    - Performances, readings and workshops, 1994-1995; 13 (Box 81)
    - Photographs
      - Ghana, 1966-1969; 2 (Box 82)
      - Native American pictographs, undated (Box 82)
      - Photographs of Joseph Bruchac, undated (Box 82)
      - Photographs by Mary Ann Bruchac Lynch, undated (Box 82)
    - Videocassettes
      - Native American Legacy: The Cloud Village- Keepers of the Earth, 7:28; Man Turns Into an Island- Keepers of the Earth, 5:34; Turtle Challenges Bear- Keepers of the Animals, 7:08. KLVX Television, Las Vegas, Nevada, 1993; YCALMSS740_0001; 1; 00:22:52 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102339935)
      - Smithsonian Institution, "National Museum of the American Indian," Indian National Campaign Video, undated; YCALMSS740_0002; 1; 00:12:29 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102339943)
      - "Measured Furrows: Vermont's Farming History," Vermont ETV, undated; YCALMSS740_0003; 1; 00:59:12 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102339950)
      - Joe Bruchac: Reading at Longwood College, 1992 September; YCALMSS740_0004; 1; 01:15:20 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102339968)
      - State of the Arts #1104, Dodge Poetry Festival: Bruchac, Tapahonso, 1992 October 11; YCALMSS740_0005; 1; 00:30:29; DUB (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102348944)
      - Joeseph Bruchac: MICA, 1994 March 17; YCALMSS740_0006; 1; 01:24:36 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102348969)
      - Many Spirits Dancing, panel discussion, 9:30 am, 2:02, 1993 May 19; YCALMSS740_0007; 1; 02:03:24 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102348977)
      - Dee Sarno, Saratoga People, Joe Bruchac interview, undated; YCALMSS740_0008; 1; 00:21:07 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102348985)
      - "Focus on Poetry: J. Bruchac," color 58 minutes, ind. gen. dub Sony VO-2800, 1982 May 25; YCALMSS740_0009; 1; 00:58:23 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002102348993)
  - Computer media
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Prentice Hall Poetry MAC Microsoft Word 4.0., 1996-ycal-1127-d-0001; 1 (Box 84)
      Box 84: Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - 1992 -poems- NDAKINNA: OUR LAND, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0002; 1 (Box 84)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - 1, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0003 (Box 84)
    - 1, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0004 (Box 84)
    - 2-1, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0005; 1 (Box 84)
    - 2-2, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0006; 1 (Box 84)
    - 3, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0007; 1 (Box 84)
    - 4, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0008; 1 (Box 84)
    - 5-1, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0009; 1 (Box 84)
    - 5-2, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0010; 1 (Box 84)
    - 6, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0011; 1 (Box 84)
    - 7 ESSAYS, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0012; 1 (Box 84)
    - 8 BREAKY, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0013; 1 (Box 84)
    - HANPRINTS: HARPER SAN FRANCISCO, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0014; 1 (Box 84)
    - HANDPRINTS, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0015; 1 (Box 84)
    - transcription of 1) Dogon Interview by D. Hill 2) Lak Lak Australia, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0016; 1 (Box 84)
    - MAC DISK AC-/… HANDPRINTS AC-8, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0017; 1 (Box 84)
    - Essays 1994, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0018; 1 (Box 84)
    - The Girl Who Married The Moon Bridgewater '94 Circle of Thanks '96, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0019; 1 (Box 84)
    - Troll: Flying With '92 Nature Co. '92, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0020; 1 (Box 84)
    - Bridgewater - Troll 93-95, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0021; 1 (Box 84)
    - Four Ancestors Bridgewater 1996, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0022; 1 (Box 84)
    - Holt Rinehart 1995 MACMILLAN 1995 Prentice Hall 1995 Simon + Schuster 1995, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0023; 1 (Box 84)
    - Joe Bruchac Rewrites of THE COYOTE BROTHERS (Rudy Martin) 1995, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0024; 1 (Box 84)
    - Coyote Brothers R. Martin The Gleaners c.1990 Microsoft Word 4.0 MAC, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0025; 1 (Box 84)
    - NMAI, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0026; 1 (Box 84)
    - SMITHSONIAN ARTICLE JUNE 1994, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0027; 1 (Box 84)
    - NMAI 1994, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0028; 1 (Box 84)
    - Bruchac Itinerary 95-96, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0029; 1 (Box 84)
    - RETURNING GIFT (1) CONTENTS (2) INTROS (3) GIFT.1 (4) GIFT.2 (5) BIOS (6) BIBLIO also on disk: "ADDRESS": addresses of contributors, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0030; 1 (Box 84)
    - RETURNING THE GIFT U. Arizona Anthology part 1, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0031; 1 (Box 84)
    - RETURNING THE GIFT U. Arizona Anthology part 2, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0032; 1 (Box 84)
    - MAC MICROSOFT WORD 3.x GIFT 1-6, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0033; 1 (Box 84)
    - RETURNING The GIFT FILES: RTGLABEL.TXT RTGREPRT.TXT Format: 1.44 DOS 5.0, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0034; 1 (Box 84)
    - WP 5.1 (IBM-formatted) GIFT 1-7, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0035; 1 (Box 84)
    - Returning the Gift 1 A-I 1990-1992, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0036; 1 (Box 84)
    - Returning the Gift Disc 2 I-Z 1990-1992, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0037; 1 (Box 84)
    - THE CROSSING PRESS THE NATIVE AMERICAN SWEAT LODGE, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0038; 1 (Box 84)
    - Joseph Bruchac HARPER NATIVE WISDOM Microsoft Word 4.0 Macintosh Plus, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0039; 1 (Box 84)
    - HARCOURT (SACRED PLACES HBJ) BETWEEN EARTH AND SKY, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0040; 1 (Box 84)
    - HARCOURT THE MAN WHO LOVED BUFFALO BUFFALO SONG, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0041; 1 (Box 84)
    - TELLING STORIES 12/95 HARCOURT TELL ME A TALE '96 Microsoft Word 4.0 Macintosh, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0042; 1 (Box 84)
    - HARCOURT 7 GENERATIONS 1995-1996, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0043; 1 (Box 84)
    - FULCRUM Glossaries KPN 95/96 KPT6, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0044; 1 (Box 84)
    - FULCRUM 92-95, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0045; 1 (Box 84)
    - Ros file FULCRUM 96 Original essays for book ROOTS OF SURVIVAL, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0046; 1 (Box 84)
    - Roots of Survival Fulcrum 1996 First Complete Draft 1995, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0047; 1 (Box 84)
    - FULCRUM LONG RIVER, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0048; 1 (Box 84)
    - DAWN LAND: THE LONG RIVER, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0049; 1 (Box 84)
    - DAWN LAND, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0050; 1 (Box 84)
    - Keepers of Life All words + names for glossary Glossary + Pronunciation, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0051; 1 (Box 84)
    - PHILOMEL -SLOW -HIAWATHA, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0052; 1 (Box 84)
    - Philomel SKY BEAR, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0053; 1 (Box 84)
    - MAKIAWISUG Story By MOHEGAN NATION With My Revisions 1996, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0054; 1 (Box 84)
    - mak. pequovoc. makiawis makiawiu cambrspec, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0055; 1 (Box 84)
    - HOLY COW PRESS TURTLE MEAT short stories, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0056; 1 (Box 84)
    - Digging Into Your Heart by Joseph Bruchac Microsoft Word 4.0 MACINTOSH Parabola Magazine, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0057; 1 (Box 84)
    - SMOKE RISING Visible Ink Smoke Rising Anthology, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0058; 1 (Box 84)
    - stories for P-3 1991 environmental mag for kids, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0059; 1 (Box 84)
      General
      Former child record (uri=/repositories/11/digital_objects/88558 - title=1996-ycal-1127-d-0059) was deleted from catalogue on [Fri Apr 26 11:18:48 EDT 2019] as matching Preservica null 15422847-aeff-45c8-aefe-feb3f53a0fd7 was deleted.
    - DIAL 1996, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0060; 1 (Box 84)
    - NATIVE AMERICAN PLAYS July '96 DIAL PUSHING UP THE SKY, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0061; 1 (Box 84)
    - DIAL BOWMAN'S STORE DIAL 8/1995 FINAL DRAFT, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0062; 1 (Box 84)
    - DIAL BOWMAN'S STORE FIRST DRAFT 1/95 DIAL, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0063; 1 (Box 84)
    - DIAL CHILDREN OF THE LONGHOUSE Eagle Song 94/95 Drafts + Final, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0064; 1 (Box 84)
    - DIAL THE ARROW OVER THE DOOR DIAL First Draft, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0065; 1 (Box 84)
    - DIAL ARROW OVER THE DOOR '97 copyedited final Microsoft Word 4.0 MAC, 1996-ycal-1127-d-0066; 1 (Box 84)
- September 1998 Acquisition, 1969-1998; 13.62 linear feet (15 boxes)
  Writings include materials relating to books, most published during the 1990s, followed by files relating to storytelling, translations, and writings of other Native American authors. Correspondence and Subject Files include additional materials relating to writings and storytelling performances.
  Organized into three subseries: Correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1994-1996; Writings, most arranged alphabetically by publisher; and Subject Files, arranged roughly alphabetically, followed by unarranged files.
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1994-1996; 15 (Box 85)
  - Writings
    - Dial Books
      - Arrow Over the Door
        - Reviews, 1998 (Box 86)
        - Background material, 1995-1996 (Box 86)
        - Correspondence and drafts, 1996-1998 (Box 86)
        - Final draft, 1996 July (Box 86)
        - Cover art, proofs, and signed copy of book, 1997 (Box 86)
        - Proofs of artwork, page proofs, and reviews, 1997 (Box 86)
        - Author's notes, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Revision, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Edited, with C. K. comments, 1996 (Box 86)
        - First draft, reference material, correspondence, and revisions, 1996 (Box 86)
      - Bowman's Store
        - Reviews, 1997 (Box 86)
        - Family tree, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Mary Ann, 1998 (Box 86)
        - Edited manuscript and master galleys, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Edited manuscript draft, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Photographs, 1998 (Box 86)
        - Book covers and signed copy of book, 1997 (Box 86)
      - Eagle Song
        - Galley proofs, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Reviews, 1997 (Box 86)
      - Pushing Up the Sky
        - Final changes correspondence, draft, and sample artwork of artist Teresa Flavin, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Artwork, 1998 (Box 86)
    - Puffin Books
      - Children of the Longhouse
        - Book cover and correspondence, 1997 (Box 86)
        - Page proofs, 1997 (Box 86)
        - Editing, 1997 (Box 86)
      - The First Strawberries: cover proof, 1998 (Box 86)
      - How Chipmunk Got His Stripes
        - Unidentified, 1998; 2 (Box 87)
        - Correspondence, 1995-98 (Box 87)
      - Heart of a Chief
        - Proof and art proofs, 1997-1998 (Box 87)
        - Page proofs, 1998 (Box 87)
        - Final draft, 1997; 2 (Box 87)
        - Edited by Cindy Kane, 1997 (Box 87)
        - Contract and chapter draft, 1997 (Box 87)
        - Draft manuscripts, 1997; 2 (Box 87)
        - Correspondence with Cindy Kane, editor, 1997 (Box 87)
    - Unidentified
      - Book proposal: Medicine Paw, undated (Box 87)
      - Correspondence and reviews, 1995-1998 (Box 87)
      - Royalties, 1995-1998 (Box 87)
      - Book catalogs, 1996-1998 (Box 87)
      - "The Coyote Brothers", 1994; 2 (Box 87)
    - Storytelling
      - NAPPS, 1989-1992; 4 (Box 87)
      - Yarnspinner, 1990-1993 (Box 88)
      - Storytelling Magazine, 1989-1996; 5 (Box 88)
      - Magazines relating to story telling, 1986-1994; 5 (Box 88)
      - On Telling Native American Stories. What to Look For, 1991-1992 (Box 88)
      - Storytelling: Kelly W. Cann. Thesis, 1997 (Box 88)
      - Storytelling. World Ethics issue, 1998 (Box 88)
      - Harbinger House. Soft Child, by Joe Hayes, 1993 (Box 88)
      - National Storytelling Association, 1997 (Box 88)
      - NSA Storytelling Store, 1998 (Box 88)
      - Publishing committee, 1995 (Box 88)
      - Tale Trader. Printed material, 1992, 1998 (Box 88)
      - Tale Trader (Corn Island Festival), 1996 (Box 88)
      - Book Links, 1995 (Box 88)
      - Rethinking Columbus, 1991 (Box 88)
      - P3 Magazine, 1989-1991 (Box 88)
    - Translators
      - Foreign publishers: Australia, 1987-1995 (Box 88)
      - Kerle Publishers (Austria), 1996-1997 (Box 88)
      - Translators: Austria, 1998, 1996 (Box 88)
      - Austria. George Bydlinski: translators. Austria. Kathe Recheis, 1985-87, 1992 (Box 88)
      - Estuaires. Revues Culturelle, 1992 (Box 89)
      - Belgium, 1990 (Box 89)
      - Dutch. Short Story Anthology, 1993 (Box 89)
      - Translators: Germany, 1990-1992 (Box 89)
      - Translators: Holland, 1985-1992 (Box 89)
      - Translators: Greece, 1989 (Box 89)
      - France. Francois Wolf-Mandroux, 1998 (Box 89)
      - Translators: France, 1996-1998 (Box 89)
      - Translators: Denmark, 1987-1992 (Box 89)
      - Czech, 1996-1998 (Box 89)
      - China, 1992 (Box 89)
      - Italy: Laura Coltelli, 1988-1989 (Box 89)
      - Translators: Italy, 1984-1997 (Box 89)
      - Japan, 1989-1993 (Box 89)
      - Luxembourg: Carlo Krieger, 1989 (Box 89)
      - Van Thienen, Manuel. Tarascon, 1990 (Box 89)
      - Translators: Poland, 1988-1996 (Box 89)
      - Translators: Russia, 1988, undated (Box 89)
      - Slovak (Ivan Stipala), 1987-1992 (Box 89)
      - Natura Cultura, 1992 (Box 89)
      - Translators, 1984-1985 (Box 89)
    - Writings of Others
      - Anderson, Jack L., 1997 (Box 89)
      - Austin, Mike, 1997 (Box 89)
      - Belin, Esther G., 1998 (Box 89)
      - Blackwolf and Gina Jones, 1996 (Box 89)
      - Bushyhead, Robert H. Cherokee stories, 1997 (Box 89)
      - Cardiff, Gladys, 1998 (Box 89)
      - Cogan, Priscilla. Compass of the Heart, 1998 (Box 90)
      - Dunning, Robert. First Peoples primer, 1996 (Box 90)
      - Hines, J. A. Man With Two Shadows, undated (Box 90)